<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<title>Xkcd on max blog</title>
<link>https://havron.xyz/blog/tags/xkcd/</link>
<description>Recent content in Xkcd on max blog</description>
<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
<language>en-us</language>
<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 13:58:27 -0400</lastBuildDate>
<atom:link href="https://havron.xyz/blog/tags/xkcd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
<title>Welcome, and meta-blogging</title>
<link>https://havron.xyz/blog/2016/welcome-and-meta-blogging/</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 13:58:27 -0400</pubDate>

<guid>https://havron.xyz/blog/2016/welcome-and-meta-blogging/</guid>
<description>

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog. It&amp;rsquo;s not too late to turn back, dear reader&amp;hellip;yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/blogging.png&#34; alt=&#34;xkcd comic: blogging&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;xkcd/741&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;curiosity-and-participation&#34;&gt;Curiosity and participation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spend a lot of time on &amp;ldquo;the web&amp;rdquo; (and while I appreciate the availability of such
a seemingly-succinct term, I feel rather guilty by attempting to account for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.livescience.com/54094-how-big-is-the-internet.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;zetta-bytes of
indexed data&lt;/a&gt;
 with two 3-letter-1-syllable words).
 The pages I browse in my leisure are usually interesting enough to keep my
 attention (admittedly, this is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TudFAEUkR9Y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;not too high of a
 threshold&lt;/a&gt;), and the best content
 is often free-of-charge. Almost any rote or technical question I have can be answered
 instantly, and accessing scores of articles, videos, podcasts, forum-threads, and opinion pieces on topics of all kinds in real-time is a given. All controllable at any
 instant from a device fitting in my pocket, of course. It is increasingly
 difficult for me &amp;ndash; born in the mid 1990&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ndash; to imagine the lives of
 those who were not (or are currently not) connected to the vast trove of hyperlinks
 that many people now rely on (and trust) for nearly everything they do.
 In exchange for all of this convenience, I must concede much of my
 privacy, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_kBlH-DQsEg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;which is in many ways dead&lt;/a&gt;.
 Despite this cost, I imagine I would miss the level of connection to the
 rest of the world which the web &amp;ndash; or a similar construct &amp;ndash; can offer,
 were it to become permanently inaccessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Occasionally, though, I find myself at a dead-end. &lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt;
does not return any results, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; has nothing interesting
to report, either. After sifting through pages-upon-pages of content, there are no
 hyperlinks left to be followed in my search for
 answers. It is often in this situation (and a few select others) when I most
 acutely recognize that I am undeniably, first-and-foremost, a &lt;em&gt;consumer&lt;/em&gt; of the
 web. I see nothing inherently wrong with this notion (or with anyone else who
 identifies in this manner), yet I still feel somewhat troubled. If my
 experience with the web were analogous to observing a vast, fantastic, and
 full-of-life formal ball &amp;ndash; yet subsequently declining to participate in a dance with
 any kind-hearted and well-intentioned person, &lt;em&gt;should I be asked&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; I posit this would be considered quite
 rude by the other attendees, the requester, and myself. Is this a reasonable
 analogy with which to encapsulate the entirety of the web and all of its nuances?
 Probably not (though I suspect any such attempt would necessitate &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xdhLQCYQ-nQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;references to cats&lt;/a&gt;).
 Ultimately, it is not as if the web is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/364/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;key-signing party&lt;/a&gt;; I need not
 participate on the web to freely enjoy its content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even so, I begin to think. What can &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; do? Do I have any valuable
 contributions to bring forth to a place in which I spend much of my time?
 I doubt I will ever be convinced of a definitive answer to this last question,
 but I start thinking of different approach vectors anyways.
 A YouTube channel? A Twitch or Twitter live-feed? How about a stack-exchange account? Dare I
 suggest a budding career as a &amp;ldquo;meme lord&amp;rdquo;? In different ways, I am intrigued by
 each of these ideas, but I envision a medium more&amp;hellip;enduring. Flexible.
 Accessible. And so, with many other worthy options available to me, I reached a
 settlement: a simple text-based web-log will do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to writing this post, I have never kept a formal log of my opinions and
reflections on any material (no journal, no diary, no audio-notes-to-self). Am I capable of doing such a task in a manner pleasing
to the general reader? Is it possible for me to accurately convey my full thoughts and
experiences within the boundaries of journalism, or at all for that matter?
Whether or not I will achieve long-term success in any of these tasks is presently unclear to me,
and I suppose I will never get a satisfying answer to my curiosities unless I take action.
And so the blog began to take form, as I write somewhat
wistfully in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vim.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vim the editor&lt;/a&gt;, using
&lt;a href=&#34;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;markdown&lt;/a&gt; syntax and bringing a
trusty &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vim.org/scripts/script.php?script_id=131&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;spell-checker&lt;/a&gt;
in tow (I can assert that many a &lt;code&gt;[s&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;zg&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;z=&lt;/code&gt; are being used).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;before-the-fun-a-disclaimer&#34;&gt;Before the fun, a Disclaimer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary driver behind this blog is having fun, and the opportunity for me to write
about material which I consider amenable to discussion in some context.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to note that any and all thoughts I now &amp;ndash; or will &amp;ndash; express on this
blog are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; intended to be
taken too seriously: my blog and its contents are never meant to be considered
the workings of a manifesto, hard-set rule-book, or
any of their ilk. Presently at 20 years of age, I find it very difficult
to imagine myself creating, understanding, or condoning formal
stances regarding my existence, purpose, or ability to cast judgment
(particularly when considering the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frontal_lobe&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;frontal lobe&lt;/a&gt; of my brain is a long ways away from reaching full maturity, and my relationship with God is far from adequately explored).
The blog can certainly change to adapt to events happening in my life, and will
always be a flexible medium which I expect to grow alongside me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before enumerating what I initially believe the blog is intended to be (and to
not be), I have a few remarks on readability and usability that I feel compelled to discuss.
You&amp;rsquo;re welcome to skip around at your leisure, as the sections of this post are
mostly independent of each other&amp;ndash;reading them in the order I placed them in is
recommended for optimal comprehension, though. Finally, I will mention that this post
covers a lot of meta-data about the blog, and is not likely to be interpreted
as very interesting to read in comparison to the content of future posts. (yes,
it&amp;rsquo;s too late to turn back, the sections are &lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/899/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;numbered&lt;/em&gt;
now&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-styling&#34;&gt;1. Styling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-1-readability&#34;&gt;1.1. Readability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The styling used in this blog is intentionally kept simple in comparison to what I
have come to expect from most web-based blogs. In general, I will give my attention
to any media (e.g. text, image, audio, video) that has a positive net value or
interesting qualities to it, but the styling choices employed by most
blogs and media sites make the process of lexing, parsing, semantically
analyzing, and evaluating (interpreting) the pattern of bits which
illuminate my screen rather strenuous and not enjoyable. However, I am
not bothered enough by this to cease media consumption altogether; I often
find the content itself to be interesting and worthwhile, and so I remain
under the auspices of their styling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-1-1-fonts-and-rendering&#34;&gt;1.1.1. Fonts and Rendering&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Vollkorn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Vollkorn&lt;/a&gt; (a serif) is the font
used to render all text on the blog at the time of writing &amp;ndash; according to &lt;a href=&#34;http://friedrichalthausen.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;its
designer&lt;/a&gt;, the font&amp;rsquo;s name is German for
&amp;lsquo;wholemeal&amp;rsquo; and is described as &amp;ldquo;bouncing and healthy&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; I have not devised my
own anthropomorphic adjectives for Vollkorn (&amp;hellip;yet). I am overall pleased
with the current rendering of the blog, and am able to read content with minimal
discomfort on mobile and desktop; however, I am acutely aware that my
presentation of text on this page may not be enjoyable for all audiences.  If
you prefer to read in &lt;a href=&#34;../raw/welcome.txt&#34;&gt;plaintext&lt;/a&gt;, or would like to render
the &lt;a href=&#34;../raw/welcome.md&#34;&gt;raw markdown&lt;/a&gt; to suit your own optimal viewing
environment, you will find links to each at the bottom of every post on the blog
(the plaintext includes all hyperlinks, re-formatted with &lt;code&gt;pandoc&lt;/code&gt; as
reference-style links).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Settling on color choices for hyperlinks, code snippets, and other pigment-related aspects of the
blog are perhaps the most difficult commitments for me to make. Out of 16,777,216
available colors, which do I choose to render in hopes of appeasing the reader
and providing maximum legibility? Are my blues too dark, my oranges too bright?
I doubt I will ever be fully-satisfied with the coloring, and anticipate
it will be perpetually tweaked. I may eventually commit to writing a guide
with recommendations of different fonts, styling, and legibility considerations
for rendering content, which could be helpful to readers whom are seeking
alternatives to browsing the blog as is. It is my utmost goal to provide an
enjoyable reading experience for all who come to the blog&amp;ndash;I am open to
suggestions on different styling, fonts, and other typography (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gust.org.pl/projects/e-foundry/tex-gyre&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TeX
Gyre&lt;/a&gt; collection and the like). You&amp;rsquo;re
welcome to send me a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/samuelhavron/blog&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pull request&lt;/a&gt; or leave comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-1-2-embedded-content-and-external-sources&#34;&gt;1.1.2. Embedded Content and External Sources&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The readability of a page further depends upon, to my eyes, the presence and
placement of embedded, non-textual media such as photographs or video (&lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/1301/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I am looking at you,
GIFs&lt;/a&gt;.). Communicating my thoughts through media other than text will be done sparingly, and often be linked-to content rather than embedded, despite the ease of embedding
images, audio, and video on the blog. I prefer to maintain a sense of continuity
in the medium I am using to convey myself; disrupting its flow without good
reason is decidedly unpleasant. I believe I feel this way in part
due to my inclination to open embedded content at its (external) source
rather than on the page itself. In defense of embedded content, seeing excerpts of
quoted text from an external source or including a well-placed image is perfectly
reasonable to me (perhaps you will see &amp;ndash; or &lt;em&gt;have seen&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; instances of
both in this very post&amp;hellip;odd&amp;hellip;). I genuinely do not mind experiencing
non-textual media, and often &lt;em&gt;enjoy&lt;/em&gt; the content when it is either befitting or adds a
layer to the content consumption which the original medium is inadequately suited to
serve &amp;ndash; the subtlety that an external link provides to-this-end is a nicety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-2-usability&#34;&gt;1.2. Usability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-2-1-navigation&#34;&gt;1.2.1. Navigation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have noticed, on the navigation links I provide &amp;ndash; either on the top
right of the page for desktop users, or in draw-table fashion from the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hamburger_button&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;hamburger button&lt;/a&gt; for mobile
users &amp;ndash; all of the options contain only two characters. It may seem rather
foolish to use such little space when a much wider screen real-estate is
available. Initially, I spelled out each navigation link as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;| blog home | categories | tags | contact me | main site |
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During earlier designs of the blog, this format appeared to render quite nicely
&amp;ndash; that is, until I made the mistake of attempting to read text on the page.
It became immediately apparent on
the desktop view that spelling out each link made for a very distracting reading
environment. The bright white color of the links certainly did not help this predicament
any, so a simpler approach is what you see now. &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt;, ~naturally~, is short for
&lt;code&gt;list&lt;/code&gt; (as in, &amp;ldquo;list all of the blog entries&amp;rdquo;; it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/1508/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Unix thing&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why have a navigation bar at all, then? Isn&amp;rsquo;t its mere existence at the heart of
my dissatisfaction with encountering distracting, eye-arresting content while
trying read a blog? Well, as the title of this subsection suggests: I include
the navigation bar because it affords crucial
&lt;em&gt;usability&lt;/em&gt;. I find that my general enjoyment of using a site starts with
an easily-accessible means of navigating to important pages, and so
I have attempted to replicate this principle-for-enjoyment on both the blog and &lt;a href=&#34;../../../index.html&#34;&gt;the main
site&lt;/a&gt;.
Furthermore, I experience a small, yet persistent level of discomfort with the complete
absence of identifying markers such as a navigation bar &amp;ndash;
however subtly I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; in fact prefer them to appear.
And that is how the navigation bar (and its contents) came to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My largest regret in including a navigation bar actually has nothing to do with
readability, and yet it bothers me deeply: for readers using a mouse
on the desktop view of the site, the navigation bar has little respect for &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fitts%27s_law&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fitts&amp;rsquo;
Law&lt;/a&gt; in the context of affording accessibility
between navigation links and blog posts themselves; it is a tremendous flaw that
is (requisite?) payment for having a more distraction-free reading environment &amp;ndash; at least
until I can devise
a better solution. I thereby elect to use the touch-screen capability of my laptop
computer to invoke hyperlinks, rather than suffer my self-imposed penalty of
mishandling Fitts&amp;rsquo; Law.
I highly encourage all readers whom find the navigation bar&amp;rsquo;s presence or interactions distracting to render the &lt;a href=&#34;../raw/welcome.md&#34;&gt;raw markdown&lt;/a&gt; in an environment which pleases them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-2-2-organization&#34;&gt;1.2.2. Organization&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There actually isn&amp;rsquo;t a whole lot to say on this aspect of the site.
With such a broad array of topics to blog about (see 2.2.),
and potentially different audiences for each,
I decided that organization by tags and categories are currently the best tool available
to me with which to sort the content I write. It turns out that I do have &lt;a href=&#34;../../../search.html&#34;&gt;search
capabilities on the site&lt;/a&gt;, but the results from major search
engines are simply not as fast, accurate, or efficient as navigating through
tags and categories. There is an interesting
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/sebz/efddfc8fdcb6b480f567&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gist on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; suggesting a
client-side script which will index, and, upon entering search terms, retrieve posts by leveraging
regular expressions&amp;ndash;did I mention that this blog is intentionally deployed
statically, and as such no tasks can be
delegated server-side? You also may have noticed that I start indexes for each section of
this post at &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo; and not &amp;lsquo;0&amp;rsquo;. Will I &amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/163/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;regret this
decision&lt;/a&gt; in the future?
Probably. It&amp;rsquo;s nothing &lt;code&gt;sed&lt;/code&gt; can&amp;rsquo;t handle if needed, though. Lastly, a keen reader
familiar with the university I attend for undergraduate studies will notice that
some of the organization, and in fact content for this very post is inspired by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.virginia.edu/tychonievich/blog/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Luther&amp;rsquo;s Meanderings&lt;/a&gt;, a blog which I
enjoy reading and highly recommend as a source of interesting, qualitative content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, is it reasonable for me to assume that my own values and preferences for
readability and usability as noted above should be fully-embraced by others whom are reading
the blog, in part, for the opportunity to experience my content through a
personal, natural lens?
I am genuinely unsure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-what-is-max-blog&#34;&gt;2. What is max blog?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-1-naming&#34;&gt;2.1. Naming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/what_xkcd_means.png&#34; alt=&#34;xkcd comic: what does the name mean? 207&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;xkcd/207&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-1-1-why-use-a-name&#34;&gt;2.1.1. Why use a name?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does a personal blog need to have a name? Could there exist biased identities,
relations, or constructs which I implicitly claim to associate with or represent
by dedicating a name to the blog? I do not believe that creating such
a label is at all necessary for my use case&amp;ndash;so why give the blog a name?
According to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Name&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, there are three common
uses for the term:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the ancient world, names were thought to be extremely powerful
and to act, in some ways, as a
separate manifestation of a person or deity. This viewpoint is responsible
both for the reluctance to use the proper name of God in Hebrew writing or
speech, as well as the common understanding in ancient magic that magical
rituals had to be carried out &amp;ldquo;in [someone&amp;rsquo;s] name&amp;rdquo;. In the Old Testament, the
names of individuals are meaningful, and a change of name indicates a change
of status.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A name for a brand or product is heavily influenced by marketing research
and strategy to be appealing and marketable. The brand name is often a
neologism or pseudoword.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A name is a term used for identification. Names can identify a class or
category of things, or a single thing, either uniquely, or within a given
context.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have yet to establish a formal stance on each of these definitions, and whether or not
any of them are applicable in any part to my personal blog. I certainly do not consider
 the name to be associated with a particular religion or be indicative of any status or title,
 nor do I desire to advertise or market it (see 2.3.).
It seems to follow that &amp;ldquo;max blog&amp;rdquo; is more-or-less in line with the 3rd definition.
I feel dissatisfied with the lack of my own formal definition which
uniquely fits what I believe are my intentions, but I will
resign to the given 3rd definition for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I hold no definitive or reasonable argument for why there may be net value or
benefit to collectively referring to these text files as &amp;ldquo;max blog&amp;rdquo;.
At the very least, I do not &lt;em&gt;intend&lt;/em&gt; to deceive readers or claim I accurately represent
a subset of the words &amp;ldquo;meticulousness, abstraction, xyz&amp;rdquo; in any satisfying or verifiable manner.
I believe it is too early to know the answers to most of my own questions on
the subject. Perhaps, though, I take the idea of a name far too seriously&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-1-2-max&#34;&gt;2.1.2. &amp;ldquo;max&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the terms themselves, I attribute much of my knowledge
of computer science to learning how to think with and recognize meticulous behavior, and
to discovering the affordances of abstraction, a construct with which many different
levels of detail come together to form a cohesive and often elegant stack&amp;ndash;
I intend to write blog entries with these core principles in mind, particularly
with entries more technical in nature. &amp;ldquo;xyz&amp;rdquo; is a
not-so-cleverly-disguised reference to the gTLD upon which this blog resides at
the time of writing (somewhere in the depths of Amazon Cloudfront and S3); &amp;ldquo;xyz&amp;rdquo; is also intended to imply &amp;ldquo;and everything else&amp;rdquo;
when read in conjunction with the former two terms (a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kleene_star&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kleene
star&lt;/a&gt; is
suitable here as well). The ordering of the
initials was entirely due to the coherent word &amp;ldquo;max&amp;rdquo; that forms given the
arrangement. Perhaps the name of the blog will eventually change, disappear, or stay for
an indefinite amount of time. My goal in this respect remains to provide a descriptor
of the blog which is not in any manner deceiving or inaccurate to the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-2-the-blog-is&#34;&gt;2.2. The blog is&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;primarily a place for me to respectfully express my own thoughts and
curiosities to the general reader on
any material &amp;ndash; be it external, or original &amp;ndash; which I either find intriguing,
important to discuss, and/or worth the reader&amp;rsquo;s attention.
In addition to technically-oriented posts, I may write in a respectful,
civilized, and open-minded
manner on religion, popular media, politics, or other very opinionated topics. I
especially encourage writing comments on opinionated posts; all entries I consider within these
bounds will be marked with the &lt;a href=&#34;../../categories/opinion/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;opinion&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; category.
On principle, if I have had an experience in which I believe public writing on may benefit the
general reader, I will write, modulo scheduling (see 3.1.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I aim to be cognizant of relevant, reported news at the time of
writing posts as a factor to posting respectful writing.
If you are reading this entry at or shortly after the time of publication, you are probably
aware of the many protests currently happening across the United States
in response to the deaths and treatment of both black citizens and state police
officers (&lt;a href=&#34;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/assets/media/img/notes/2016/07/RTSH3XR/lead_large.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this
image&lt;/a&gt; by Reuter&amp;rsquo;s Jonathan Bachman is particularly striking);
the country&amp;rsquo;s two major political parties are due to hold their respective
national conventions very soon (in which candidates for U.S. Presidency are formally
nominated); the augmented-reality industry is (possibly) at our footsteps
 with the recent release of the iOS and Android application &amp;lsquo;Pok&amp;eacute;mon GO&amp;rsquo;; countless other
 events of interest are being discussed by the general public (or not at all) in
 the U.S. and across the world.
I do not intend to address most current news in any reasonable manner, but I
do intend to be cognizant of it when writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the technical side of things, I aim to write about my academic interests and
inquiries, and communicate ideas and thoughts on relevant academic publications
and material. I hope to invite qualitative discussion from readers on my technical
posts; each entry I consider technical in nature will have the &lt;code&gt;technical&lt;/code&gt; category label.
I am also open to collaborative authorship on technical blog posts&amp;ndash;please
contact me if you are interested in this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned previously in the blog&amp;rsquo;s disclaimer, I do expect the blog to grow
and change as I do. I can also imagine the necessity of maintaining strictly
separate blogs for opinionated and technical content. If you are particularly
inclined to see this change, you are welcome to comment or contact me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-3-the-blog-is-not&#34;&gt;2.3. The blog is not&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a place for blatant/explicit self-advertising or self-promotion. I have little
interest in spreading word of my blog or its posts without holding good reason,
nor to write about myself in a manner of qualification or suggestion of suitability
for a particular paid role or opportunity.
In the context of sharing or spreading word of a particular blog post I have
written, a &amp;ldquo;good reason&amp;rdquo; means I believe that sharing such content is directly helpful
to the recipient at the expenditure of their time, and that I believe I am not
sharing such a post with explicit self-promotion in mind.
I do not take any issue with those whom find, read, and subsequently recommend or share the
blog on their own, nor do I have any issue with those whom directly ask me
about my blog and its contents. You are welcome to do any of those things as you
see fit. Keep in mind the &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CreativeCommons
license&lt;/a&gt; at the bottom of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the blog is not a place for hateful, disrespectful, maligned, or discriminatory
content or discussion of any kind (either from myself or from readers). Please contact me
if you believe I may have written insensitive content, so that I may rectify it
and/or open discussion for it at length in a respectful manner with an appropriate audience.
I have no intention of offending my readers, and I value any feedback you may
have for me in this context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not publish content that I consider to have little value to my
readers and myself; this includes sponsored advertisements to for-profit
organizations. Appropriate non-profit organizations or causes which are
pertinent to the subject of my writing are welcome to a reference or
potential recommendation from me, provided that including such information
may be helpful to the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the best of my ability, these are the qualities of the blog I intend to keep.
Other suggestions are welcome in the comments&amp;ndash;this is a highly flexible,
amendable set of qualities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-welcome-again&#34;&gt;3. Welcome, again&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-1-schedule&#34;&gt;3.1. Schedule&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be frank, I do not have a set schedule for publishing posts. I would like to write on some
order of a bi-weekly or monthly basis, though I do not consider myself beholden to
arbitrary quotas if it comes at the expense of content quality and purpose.
Similarly, I will not write on a topic longer than is needed to communicate my
full thoughts &amp;ndash; I can imagine, however, needing to redress a topic or return to
a topic in which I have more meaningful and relevant words to write about. Will
every post be of similar length to this one? Probably not at all&amp;hellip;but I suspect several
posts in the future will be even longer.
If there is a particular topic of interest or piece of published content which
you would like to see a blog post on here, including my full thoughts on
the material, you are welcome to contact me!
(this could be silly in nature, a research-oriented topic, a difficult moral
or ethical situation, or anything in between; as long as you
believe that my writing on such material would be
beneficial to you and the general blog reader.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-2-the-reader-and-preview&#34;&gt;3.2. The Reader, and Preview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would maintaining an e-mail notification list or similar construct to alert subscribers of a new
post be useful for the ardent reader?
Perhaps, but part of me does not like the idea of announcing the presence of new
content, as if to suggest that my writing has a priority to be read &amp;ndash; an
implicit assertion or claim that the best use of a person&amp;rsquo;s time and attention
is to consume the content I created.
I am more fond of the idea that those whom want to read the blog do so of their
own volition and initiative.
Thank you for expending your personal time to scan and interpret the 4101
words I typed (yes, I had to increment that number by the virtue of typing
it out. What a fun bug that could be in a program!). Regardless of whether
or not you agreed with or enjoyed the content, I do appreciate those whom read in
earnest to-the-end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have made it this far, thanks for reading! I am aware that this post
may come across as rather boring&amp;hellip;but I am pleased nonetheless to have
communicated relevant meta-data about the blog. Stay tuned for more
inherently interesting (and fun!) posts that I look forward to writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up next: discussion of a paper recently published in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ieee-security.org/TC/SP2016/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;37th IEEE
S&amp;amp;P symposium&lt;/a&gt; which I find amenable to qualitative discussion, or at least
amenable to the enumeration of my own thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
